Guide to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives: Small Photograph Collections ALBA.PHOTO.036
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives: Small Photograph Collections
1928-1992
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives
ALBA.PHOTO.036
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
This collection contains a number of photograph collections, mostly donated by veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, that were deemed too small to catalogue individually. All of the photographs were separated from corresponding Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) manuscript collections at the Tamiment Library. The images include scenes of the battlefield and daily life in the International Brigades during the Spanish Civil War, Spanish civilians and locales during the War, portraits and group shots of American volunteers in Spain and in the pre- and post-Spanish Civil War years, and images of Dolores Ibarruri, among other subjects.
Provenance
Most of these photographs, and their corresponding manuscript collections, came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University. The Colodny, Rucker, Carter and Friedman collections were donated to the Tamiment Library, NYU in 2003 and 2004.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Historical/Biographical Note
Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives: Small Photograph Collections is a compilation of images that have been separated from ALBA archival collections. For historical/biographical information on each individual, consult the guide to the corresponding manuscript collection. The images include scenes of the battlefield and daily life in the International Brigades during the Spanish Civil War, Spanish civilians and locales during the War, portraits and group shots of American volunteers in Spain and in the pre- and post-Spanish Civil War years, and images of Dolores Ibarruri, among other subjects.
Scope and Content Note
The collection is a compilation of photographic prints, slides and negatives relating to the Spanish Civil War and the Abraham Lincoln Brigade associated with, or collected by, various individuals.
Series I: Carl Geiser Collection. The Carl Geiser Collection contains 10 prints including images of Geiser in Spain and in a French concentration camp, images of Sidney Rosenblatt in Spain and Frank Blackman with Paul Scott in Toronto. Also one negative of troops at the front on a truck. The negative does not match any print in the collection.
Series II: Steve Nelson Collection. The Steve Nelson Collection contains approximately 25 prints including images of volunteers resting and relaxing, Steve Nelson in Spain and the United States, Marion Noble and Don Eggert at Belchite, Oliver Law, Larry Lustgarten in Spain. VALB veterans events post-SCW. It also contains approximately 30 negatives including images of Dolores Ibarruri, Herman Klein's identity card and troops at the front. Negatives do not match prints.
Series III: Theodore Cogswell Collection. The Theodore Cogswell Collection contains seven prints, including images of Cogswell in Spain, and volunteers resting/relaxing in Murcia
Series IV: Alvah Bessie Collection. The Alvah Bessie Collection contains twelve prints including combat images, tribute to Bessie in Berkeley, CA, and publicity photos from the film "To Die in Madrid."
Series V: Lawrence Cane Collection. The Lawrence Cane Collection contains one image of the veterans returning to New York City from Spain.
Series VI: Harry Hakam Collection. The Harry Hakam Collection contains approximately 20 prints including images of Hakkam in Spain, air combat, Ralph Bates in Spain, volunteers resting/relaxing behind the lines, Robert Steck speaking to the troops in Spain. One negative of troops resting/relaxing behind the lines. The negative matches a print in the collection.
Series VII: Edward Lending Collection. The Edward Lending Collection contains three prints including images of Lending in Spain with Samuel Harold Levinger, Maurice Hawkins, Jack Shafran, Ken Graeber, Sam Schiff, Peter Frye, Felix Kuzman, and Bill Skinner.
Series VIII: Vincent Lossowski Collection. The Vincent Lossowski Collection contains one portrait of Lossowski during WWII and another 8 x 10 print with a portrait of Lossowski, Bob Thompson, Larry Cane, Mike Jimenez, Irving Goff and Neil Wesson titled "The Have Served with Honor".
Series IX: Mark Rauschwald Collection. The Mark Rauschwald Collection contains approximately 100 prints including Rauschwald's artwork, anti-fascist demonstrations in New York City, Phil Bard at a May Day event in the U.S., Rauschwald in the U.S., Arnold Dudra in the U.S., Arnold LeHavre in the U.S. Harry Mensh in the U.S. Also contains eleven slides of Rauschwald's artwork.
Series X: Ely J. Sack Collection. The Ely J. Sack Collection contains approximately twenty prints including portraits of Sack, Sack and Morris Brier resting/relaxing behind the lines, and Ely Sack with Edith Sack and Louise Stone.
Series XI: Mildred Rackley Collection. The Mildred Rackley Collection contains two prints including one image of an ambulance and one image of medical personnel including Oscar Telge, Wilhelm Holst, Eve Merrimen, Stanislaus Rubint and Edward Barsky [?].
Series XII: Leon Torgoff Collection. The Leon Torgoff's Collection contains five prints including images of Torgoff's childhood and a portrait with Jada Torgoff. One negative matches the print of Leon and Jada Torgoff.
Series XIII: Neil Wesson Collection. The Neil Wesson Collection contains approximately 45 prints including images of Wesson at the front with Andrew Pape, Sid Horowitz and Jose Baldugne, relaxing with Robert Merriman and Alfred Blasa, at Dolores Ibarruri's house with Ruth Wesson, Alva Bessie, and Hy Rassner, WWII portraits, and with Bob Raven and Don Thayer in the German Democratic Republic. Also contains images of Dachau Concentration Camp survivors and victims.
Series XIV: Paul Wendorf Collection. The Paul Wendorf Collection contains three prints including images of Wendorf at the front firing a machine gun, relaxing behind the lines, and a proletarian monument [location].
Series XV: Elias Begelman Collection. The Elias Begelman Collection contains two prints, a portrait of Begelman in Spain and one of Artur Dorf in the U.S. (1944).
Series XVI: Howard Goddard Collection. The Howard Goddard collection contains approximately twenty prints including three images of Goddard en route to Spain with Yale Stuart, two images of Jose Valledor with Bill Alexander in London (1985) and twelve images of the Sixtieth Anniversary Homenaje in Barcelona (1996).
Series XVII: Miriam Sigel Collection. The Miriam Sigel Collection contains four prints including portraits of [Paul] Sigel, Victor Tishup and an unidentified individual.
Series XVIII: Frank C. Costanzo Collection. The Frank C. Costanzo Collection contains one portrait of Costanzo.
Series XIX: George Chaiken Collection. The George Chaiken Collection contains a portrait of Pedro Jimenez and two images of Spanish child refugees.
Series XX: Sylvia Boehm Acker Collection. The Sylvia Boehm Acker Collection contains one portrait of George Boehm in Paris and one portrait of George Boehm in Spain.
Series XXI: Robert Colodny Collection. The Robert Colodny Collection contains fourteen prints including images of American Volunteers with pre-WWI non-recoil cannon, "Chato" a snub-nosed Soviet fighter plane, U.S. volunteers in winter gear, an American kitchen crew, Mitchell Diggs and Dave Doran with an armored vehicle in Teruel, and a memorial to victims of Spanish fascism, as well as portraits of Herman Bottcher, George Cullinen, Kenneth Shaker, Bill Wheeler and Milton Wolff, and one of Fredericka Martin and Francis Patai in Cuernavaca, Mexico.
Series XXII: James Bernard Rucker Collection. The James Bernard Rucker Collection contains two prints including one image of the 317th Medical Battalion of the 92nd Infantry, Company D and one image of Decoration Day with Rucker and the President of the United Negro Veterans.
Series XXIII: Martin Friedman Collection. The Martin Friedman Collection contains two prints including one portrait of Friedman in Spain and one image an unidentified individual.
Series XXIV: Edward Carter Collection. The Edward Carter Collection contains three images including a portrait of Carter in WWII, an image of Carter with a submachine gun and an image of the container ship SSG Edward A. Carter Jr.
Series XXV: Mito Kruth Collection. The Mito Kruth Collection contains 62 images removed from Kruth's disassembled scrapbook including images of Helen Leiviska (who would later become his wife) and Kruth family and friends resting and relaxing and images of the Vermont countryside. The scrapbook has been photocopied to preserve the original order.
Series XXVI: Irving Jenkins Collection. The Irving Jenkins Collection contains 34 images including Jenkins with Bernie Danchik and Dorothy Tucker in Paris and Barcelona, troops marching in Barcelona, Barcelona and Paris street scenes and steamships. Jenkins was a Cornell University student and athlete who traveled to Barcelona in the summer of 1936 to participate in the People's Olympics.
Series XXVII: Benjamin Leider Collection. The Benjamin Leider Collection consists of 34 prints, including portraits and group shots taken before Leider's service in Spain, a portrait showing Leider in the cockpit of a plane, and an image of a large sign/poster of Leider, apparently carried in a parade or demonstration in New York City after his death in Spain.
Series XXVIII: Douglas Wayne Male Collection. The Douglas Wayne Male Collection consists of 6 prints, including informal group and individual shots taken in the field in Spain. Several are associated with and annotated by Male's friend and fellow-volunteer Boleslaw Sliwon; another, showing African-American volunteer Sterling Rochester, with a group of Spanish soldiers, is annotated in a different hand.
Series XXIX: Milton White Collection. The Milton White Collection contains 15 prints and one transparency, mostly of unidentified women (probably relatives). There are also some group portraits of US Army and US Army Airforce officers based in Miami. There are two prints of Milton White.
Series XXX: Robert Taylor Collection. The Robert Taylor Collection consists of four prints, three of them group shots including Taylor during the Spanish Civil War and the fourth a photo from a VALB event in 1984.
Arrangement
The sequence of series follows the sequence of ALBA Collection numbers for the corresponding manuscript collections, with a few collections added out of sequence at the end. Folders are arranged alphabetically by topic within each series. The photographic prints are identified by four numbers separated by colons. The first number refers to the collection number, the second to the box number, the third to the folder number, and the fourth to the individual print. For example, the first print in this collection is labeled 36:1:1:1. Negatives are numbered in the same fashion and if there is a matching print, the print number is listed below the negative number.
The files are grouped into twenty-eight series:
Missing Title
I, Carl Geiser
II, Steve Nelson
III, Theodore Cogswell
IV, Alvah Bessie
V, Lawrence Cane
VI, Harry Hakam
VII, Edward Lending
VIII, Vincent Lossowski
IX, Mark Rauschwald
X, Ely J. Sack
XI, Mildred Rackley
XII, Leon Torgoff
XIII, Neil Wesson
XIV, Paul Wendorf
XV, Elias Begelman
XVI, Howard Goddard
XVII, Miriam Sigel
XVIII, Frank C. Costanzo
XIX, George Chaiken
XX, Sylvia Boehm Acker
XXI, Robert Colodny
XXII, James Bernard Rucker
XXIII, Martin Friedman
XXIV, Edward Carter
XXV, Mito Kruth
XXVI, Irving Jenkins
XXVII, Benjamin Leider
XXVIII, Douglas Wayne Male
XXIX, Milton White
XXX, Robert Taylor
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
ALBA #20 Theodore Cogswell Papers
ALBA #71 Vincent Lossowski Papers
ALBA #202 Sylvia Boehm Acker Papers
ALBA #228 Edward Carter Papers
Milton White Papers (ALBA 278)
Robert Taylor Papers (ALBA 110)
ALBA #4 Carl Geiser Papers
ALBA #8 Steve Nelson Papers
ALBA #24 Alvah Bessie Papers
ALBA #29 Lawrence Cane Papers
ALBA #46 Harry Hakam Papers ALBA #68 Edward Lending Papers ALBA #92 Mark Rauschwald Papers ALBA #94 Ely J. Sack Papers ALBA #97 Mildred Rackley Papers ALBA #109 Leon Torgoff Papers ALBA #117 Neil Wesson Papers
ALBA #120 Paul Wendorf Papers ALBA #124 Elias Begelman Papers ALBA #126 Howard Goddard Papers ALBA #192 Miriam Sigel Papers ALBA #194 Benjamin Leider Papers ALBA #195 Frank C. Costanzo Papers ALBA #200 George Chaikin Papers ALBA #211 Robert Colodny Papers ALBA #212 James Bernard Rucker Papers ALBA #218 Martin Friedman Papers
ALBA # 223 Douglas Wayne Male Papers ALBA #240 Mito Kruth Papers
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American; Barcelona (Spain); Albacete (Spain); Slides (photographs); Negatives (photographic); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Pictorial works; Seville (Spain); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- African Americans; Black-and-white photographs.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- International brigades.; Political prisoners -- Spain; Friedman, Martin, 1914-1966; Rauschwald, Mark, 1908-1985; Costanzo, Frank Carl, 1912-; Simon, Mildred Rackley, 1906-2003; Chaikin, George, 1908-1992; Rochester, Sterling.; Carter, Edward A., -1963; Cane, Lawrence, 1912-1976; Sack, Ely Joseph, 1937-1992; Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1904-1985; Begelman, Elias, 1912-1959; Acker, Sylvia Boehm.; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional, XV; Wendorf, Paul; White, Milton, 1917-; Torgoff, Leonard Sloan, 1916-1937; Hakam, Harry, 1913-1996; Sliwon, Boleslaw; Jenkins, Irving; Kruth, Mito, 1899-; Siegel, Joseph; Goddard, Howard, 1911-1997; Leider, Benjamin, 1901-1937; Geiser, Carl; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Bay Area Post; Cogswell, Theodore R.; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Colodny, Robert Garland.; Lossowski, Vincent, 1914-1984; Rucker, James Bernard, 1912-1992; Lending, Edward Isaac, 1912-2003; Nelson, Steve, 1903-1993; Wesson, Neil, 1906-1974
- Series I: Carl Geiser Collection
  - Blackman, Frank: With Paul Scott, Post-SCW, Toronto, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Geiser, Carl: Portrait, Post-SCW, Italian Cemetery, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Geiser, Carl: With 11 Unidentified Men, Concentration Camp, Gours (France), ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Geiser, Carl: With Italian Group, Post-SCW, French Cemetery, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Geiser, Carl: With 20 Unidentified Men, Concentration Camp, Gurs (France), ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hansbout, Urbarin: Portrait, WWII, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rosenblatt, Sidney: Portrait, Albacete, Jun 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rosenblatt, Sidney: Portrait and Clipping from New York Daily News, Albacete, Jun 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rubens, Irene: At Sidney Rosenblatt's Grave, American Cemetery, Espinal (France), Aug 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Negative: At the Front, Non-Combat, Troops on Truck, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Steve Nelson Collection
  - Behind the Lines: Oliver Law, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Larry Lustgarten and Three Unidentified Soldiers, Jul 4, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, ? Williams, Steve Nelson, Martin William Hourihan, Mirco Markovicz, [Harry] Haywood and Unidentified Man, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Humble, Pat: Boarding Bus, Post-SCW, US, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Luba, Charlie: International Brigade Memorial Wall at Cemetery, France, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - McMullen, Martha: Sitting with Dog, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Nelson, Steve: Contact Sheet, Portraits, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Nelson, Steve: Labor Defender, Cover, "Release all Class War Prisoners", Jun 1930 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Nelson, Steve: Portrait, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nelson, Steve: With Dolores Ibarruri, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Nelson, Steve: With Unidentified Man, post-SCW, Guernica, Jun 1, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Noble, Marion: With Don Eggert, Belchite, Oct 21, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Political Poster: French Communist Party, post-SCW, Paris, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Rice, Charles Owen: Portrait, [1976] (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ross, Carl: Family, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Soldiers Monument: "To Our Fallen Comrades-Our Victory is Your Vengeance", Jun 1937 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Unidentified Groups and Individuals: Contact Sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - VALB: Veterans Event, post-SCW, US, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Vidali, Vitorio: Speaking at Microphone with Three Unidentified Men, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Negatives: At the Front, Non-Combat, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Negatives: Dolores Ibarruri, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Negatives: Herman Klein, Identity Card, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Negatives: Unidentified Groups and Individuals, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Series III: Theodore Cogswell Collection
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Murcia, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Cogswell, Theodore [?]: Portrait, Spain, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Cogswell, Theodore [?]: Standing by Automobile, Spain, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Series IV: Alvah Bessie Collection
  - At the Front: Combat, Injured Soldier, To Die in Madrid, Publicity Photos, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - At the Front: Combat, Running Soldier, To Die in Madrid, Publicity Photos, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - At the Front: Combat, Soldiers Charging with Rifles, To Die in Madrid, Publicity Photos, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - At the Front: Combat, Soldiers Firing from Trench, To Die in Madrid, Publicity Photos, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Brown, Edmund J. (Jerry): VALB: Tribute to Alvah Bessie (Thirty-ninth Anniversary Dinner), Berkeley CA, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Brown, Edmund J. (Jerry): VALB: Tribute to Alvah Bessie (Thirty-ninth Anniversary Dinner), with Alvah Bessie, Berkeley CA, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Brown, Edmund J. (Jerry): VALB: Tribute to Alvah Bessie (Thirty-ninth Anniversary Dinner), with Harry Bridges and Al Richmond, Berkeley CA, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Caballero, Largo: With Five Unidentified Men, To Die in Madrid, Publicity Photos, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Ibarruri, Dolores: Portrait, To Die in Madrid, Publicity Photos, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Lincoln Brigade: Shipboard, Signed by Kenneth Bridenthal, Aaron B. Johnson, George Pulkkinen, Joseph Sinnot, John Kolaga, Francis J. Herman, Isadore Wittels, John Wegrzynek, Joseph Benson, Fritz Grell, Roger Hargrave, Francis Clair Sanford, Gabriel Jack Quinones, Joseph Sakolanekas, Mike Hill, Jack Kramer, Joseph Vaughan, Jacob Bergen, Don Sanborn, John Day, Jack Altman, Harry B. Patterson, Moe Fishman, Herman Barr, ca.1938 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Spanish Clergy: Blessing the Franco "Crusade," To Die in Madrid, Publicity Photos, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - de Unamuno, Miguel: With Seven Journalists, To Die in Madrid, Publicity Photos, Oct 1936 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - VALB: Tribute to Alvah Bessie (Thirty-ninth Anniversary Dinner), Unidentified Dancer, Berkeley, CA, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Series V: Lawrence Cane Collection
  - Demonstration: Veterans Return, "Welcome Home," NYC, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Series VI: Harry Hakam Collection
  - At the Front: Combat, Air Combat, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Bates, Ralph: In Front of Truck, Albacete, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Bates, Ralph: Speaking to Troops, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation [Includes James Cunningham and Stuart Yale], ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Damaged Buildings: post-SCW, Belchite, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Fascist Fortifications: post-SCW, Jarama, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Fishman, Moe: with ?, Spain, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Hakam, Harry: Portrait, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Hakam, Harry: Returning from Spain with Harry Fisher, Joe North, Oscar Hunter and Two Unidentified Men, Ile de France, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Hakam, Harry: with Valerie Hakam and Ruth Hakam, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Hakam, Harry: with ?, ?, Sean F., Douglas Roach, Harry Fisher, ?, ?, Jarama, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Individuals: Unidentified, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Steck, Robert: Speaking to Troops, Albacete, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Negative: Behind the Lines, Rest and Relaxation, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Series VII: Edward Lending Collection
  - At the Front: Non-Combat, ?, [Ben Kasinap], Samuel Harold Levinger, ?, ?, ?, ?, Maurice Hawkins, Jack Sharfran, Edward Lending, Norman Berkowitz, Spain, ca.1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, ?, ?, ?, Larry Maynard, ?, ?, ?, ?, Ken Graeber, ?, Sam Schiff, ?, ?, ?, ?, ?, Peter Frye, ?, ?, Edward Lending, ?, Felix Kuzman, ? Payne, ?, ?, Bill Skinner, ?, Lester Gittelson, ?, ?, Benicasim, Oct 1937 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Lending, Edward: Dictating to Clerk, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Series VIII: Vincent Lossowski Collection
  - Lossowski, Vincent: Portrait, WWII, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - They Have Served With Honor: Bob Thompson, Larry Cane, Vincent Lossowski, Mike Jimenez, Irving Goff, Neil Wesson, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Series IX: Mark Rauschwald Collection
  - Anti-Fascist Demonstration: 17 Battery Place, New York, Nov 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Fascist Demonstration: Opposite German Consulate, New York, Nov 1936 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Artwork, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bard, Phil: May Day Event, U.S., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Demonstrations/Strikes: U.S., 1930s (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dudra [?], Arnold: At the Concrete Swimming Hole, Mar 1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dudra [?], Arnold: Portraits, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dudra [?], Arnold: with Deer, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dudra [?], Arnold: with Three Unidentified Men, Alabama, Mar 1934 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - LeHavre, Arnold: Portrait, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Mensh, Harry: At Home, [1935] (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rauschwald, Mark: At the Beach, Sandy Hook, NJ, Jun 1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rauschwald, Mark: At the Beach with Bada and Trombino, Sandy Hook, NJ, Jun 1933 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Rauschwald, Mark: Book Covers, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Rauschwald, Mark: Portraits, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Rauschwald, Mark: Posing with Cannon, Fort Hancock, NJ, Jun 1933 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Rauschwald, Mark: Studio, Feb 1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Rauschwald, Mark: with Family [?], undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Rauschwald, Mark: with Vaughn Love and Unidentified Woman, Veterans Dinner, U.S., Feb 1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Shipboard, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Soviet Pavilion: World's Fair, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Spanish Civilians, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 21a)
  - Strike: Fulton Street, Brooklyn, Dec 1935 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Veterans Dinner, Feb 1957 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Slides: Artwork, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Series X: Ely J. Sack Collection
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Ely Sack (l) and Morris Brier (r), Jun 1938 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Ely Sack (sitting in chair), Morris Brier (front, sitting), ?, ?, ?, Catalonia, Jun 1938 (Box 2, Folder 26)